<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Lukas Scarfe</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Lukas Scarfe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2026 Lukas Scarfe</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Coleus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plants/red-coleus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plants/red-coleus/</guid>
      <description>There are a million varieties of Coleus plant. In low-light or shady conditions, these plants often produce more chlorophyll to capture what little light is available, causing their deep crimson or burgundy leaves to revert and develop prominent green margins or veining. This natural transformation creates a beautiful, high-contrast look that softens the plant’s appearance compared to the solid, intense reds they exhibit when grown in full sun.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/plants/red-coleus/feature_2026-01-16.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angel Wing Begonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plants/angel-wing-begonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plants/angel-wing-begonia/</guid>
      <description>The Angel Wing begonia is a popular hybrid houseplant prized for its striking, asymmetrical leaves that resemble the outstretched wings of an angel. These leaves often feature a deep forest-green color on top with shimmering silver speckles and a vibrant, contrasting burgundy or red underside. Under the right light conditions, the plant produces drooping clusters of delicate waxy flowers in shades ranging from bright white to soft pink.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/plants/angel-wing-begonia/feature_2026-01-15.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ficus Elastica</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plants/ficus-elastica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plants/ficus-elastica/</guid>
      <description>The Ficus Elastica, commonly known as the Rubber Plant, is a robust indoor tree admired for its large, glossy leaves that possess a thick, leathery texture. These broad oval leaves emerge from a distinctive pinkish sheath and can range in color from a deep, waxy green to a dramatic &amp;ldquo;Burgundy&amp;rdquo; or even variegated patterns of cream and lime. Because of its sturdy upright growth habit, it serves as a sophisticated focal point in interior design while being remarkably effective at filtering indoor air.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/plants/ficus-elastica/feature_2026-01-15.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchid Cactus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plants/orchid-cactus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plants/orchid-cactus/</guid>
      <description>The Orchid Cactus, known botanically as Epiphyllum, is a captivating tropical plant that defies the standard image of a desert-dwelling succulent. Native to the dense rainforests of Central and South America, these plants are epiphytes, meaning they grow suspended in the jungle canopy, anchoring their roots in the mossy bark and decaying organic matter of tree forks rather than in the soil. Despite their common name, they are not orchids, though they share the same tree-dwelling lifestyle. Their appearance is defined by long, flat, trailing stems that lack the harsh spines of their desert cousins, instead featuring scalloped or wavy edges that gracefully drape from hanging baskets. The true glory of the Orchid Cactus lies in its spectacular, oversized blooms, which can reach up to 10 inches in diameter. These flowers are famous for their neon-bright palette, ranging from fiery reds and electric purples to soft pinks and sunset yellows. Some species, most notably the Epiphyllum oxypetalum or &amp;ldquo;Queen of the Night,&amp;rdquo; are strictly nocturnal, unfurling their massive, fragrant white petals only after dusk and withering by dawn—a fleeting, moonlit performance that has gained a cult following among plant enthusiasts. In contrast, many modern hybrids have been bred to bloom during the day, offering a more enduring display of their intricate, multi-petaled geometry throughout the spring and early summer. Cultivating an Orchid Cactus requires a departure from typical cactus care. Because they are &amp;ldquo;jungle cacti,&amp;rdquo; they thrive in bright, filtered light rather than harsh, direct sun, which can scorch their delicate stems. They prefer a humid environment and a porous, well-draining potting medium—often a mix of peat, perlite, and orchid bark—to mimic their native arboreal habitat. Unlike desert species, they do not tolerate complete dehydration; they should be watered once the top inch of soil feels dry. A crucial &amp;ldquo;secret&amp;rdquo; to securing their legendary blooms is providing a cool, dry rest period during the winter months. By keeping the plant in a cooler room (around 50–55°F) and significantly reducing water for several weeks, you trigger the formation of flower buds that will erupt into a floral masterpiece as the weather warms. With their lush, cascading habit and exotic, jewel-toned blossoms, these plants offer a rewarding blend of structural drama and ethereal beauty.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/plants/orchid-cactus/feature_2026-01-14.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tradescantia Nanouk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/plants/tradescantia-nanouk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/plants/tradescantia-nanouk/</guid>
      <description>The Tradescantia Nanouk, scientifically known as Tradescantia albiflora &amp;lsquo;Nanouk&amp;rsquo;, is a horticultural masterpiece that has taken the indoor gardening world by storm with its almost ethereal, candy-colored foliage. Developed in the Netherlands in 2012 through a rigorous breeding program, this patented cultivar was specifically designed to be more robust, compact, and vibrantly colored than its older &amp;ldquo;Spiderwort&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Inch Plant&amp;rdquo; relatives. Its leaves are its crowning glory: thick, lance-shaped, and slightly waxy, they feature a stunning variegated pattern of creamy white, sage green, and brilliant fuchsia stripes. Perhaps most striking is the underside of each leaf, which is a solid, vivid magenta that creates a glowing effect when the plant is viewed from below in a hanging basket. Unlike many of its trailing cousins that can become sparse and spindly, the Nanouk has shorter internodes—the space between leaves—which results in a much denser, lusher appearance that looks equally beautiful cascading over a shelf or sitting as a bushy centerpiece on a tabletop.To maintain the high-definition neon hues that make the Nanouk so popular, bright, indirect light is an absolute necessity. While it can tolerate lower light levels, the plant will often &amp;ldquo;revert&amp;rdquo; to a plain green to maximize its chlorophyll production, and its stems will stretch out in a &amp;ldquo;leggy&amp;rdquo; search for sun, sacrificing its compact charm. A spot near an east- or north-facing window is ideal, providing the energy it needs to produce its small, star-shaped white and yellow flowers that peek out from pink buds during the growing season. Despite its exotic appearance, it is a remarkably resilient plant, though it does have one specific quirk: its fleshy leaves are highly sensitive to standing water. When watering, it is crucial to apply moisture directly to the soil at the base of the plant rather than splashing the foliage, as trapped droplets can lead to unsightly brown spots or fungal rot. In terms of long-term care, the Nanouk thrives in a well-draining potting medium, often enriched with perlite or orchid bark to ensure the roots never sit in stagnant water. It prefers to have the top inch of its soil dry out before receiving a thorough soak. Because it is such a vigorous grower, it may require repotting annually and benefits from regular &amp;ldquo;pinching&amp;rdquo;—the practice of snipping off the growing tips to encourage the plant to branch out and stay full. These trimmings need not go to waste, as the Nanouk is famously easy to propagate; a simple stem cutting placed in water or directly into moist soil will typically sprout new roots within a week. This combination of &amp;ldquo;Insta-worthy&amp;rdquo; aesthetics and a forgiving, fast-growing nature makes it a perfect bridge plant for beginners looking to move beyond basic greenery into the world of colorful, variegated tropicals.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/plants/tradescantia-nanouk/feature_2026-01-13.jpg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-dimensional quantum key distribution with Qubit-like states</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/fourier-qubits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/fourier-qubits/</guid>
      <description>We introduce a high-dimensional QKD protocol using qubit-like states that are superpositions of only two computational basis states. This simplifies experimental implementation while providing a measured sifted key rate above 1 bit per photon in a noisy 4-dimensional channel.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/research/fourier-qubits/featured_4D_HD_Pubs_crop.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting atmospheric turbulence for secure quantum communications in free space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/turbulence-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/turbulence-prediction/</guid>
      <description>We present a machine learning approach to forecast atmospheric turbulence ($C_n^2$) up to 12 hours in advance. By predicting channel conditions, we can determine optimal timing for secure key exchange in free-space quantum networks.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/research/turbulence-prediction/featured_taroqqo.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast adaptive optics for high-dimensional quantum communications in turbulent channels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/fast-ao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/fast-ao/</guid>
      <description>We employ a high-speed Adaptive Optics (AO) system to correct real-time wavefront distortions in spatial modes, significantly reducing crosstalk and error rates for OAM-based QKD in turbulent environments.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/research/fast-ao/featured.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reading/</guid>
      <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
