<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Lukas Scarfe</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Lukas Scarfe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2026 Lukas Scarfe</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>High-dimensional quantum key distribution with Qubit-like states</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/fourier-qubits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/fourier-qubits/</guid>
      <description>The research paper titled &amp;ldquo;High-dimensional quantum key distribution with qubit-like states&amp;rdquo; introduces a novel protocol for high-dimensional quantum key distribution (HD-QKD) that utilizes a new class of states called Fourier-qubits, or F-qubits, to enhance the efficiency and noise tolerance of quantum communications. Traditional HD-QKD protocols often rely on mutually unbiased bases (MUBs), where the secondary basis consists of balanced superpositions of all possible states in the logical basis, which can be technically challenging to implement and detect with high efficiency in certain degrees of freedom like orbital angular momentum (OAM). In this study, the authors propose replacing the traditional Fourier basis with F-qubits, which are qubit-like states formed by superpositions of only two logical states at a time with specific phase relationships derived from the roots of unity. This approach moves away from the requirement of full mutual unbiasedness while still providing a rigorous bound on the information leaked to a potential eavesdropper, thereby maintaining the security of the quantum channel. The researchers experimentally validated their protocol using a four-dimensional system based on the OAM degree of freedom of light, subjecting the signal to a noisy environment simulated by a turbulent cell and utilizing adaptive optics for correction. A key advantage of the F-qubit basis is its superior detection efficiency; because these states have a larger spatial intensity distribution compared to traditional MUB states, they utilize more of the active area of spatial light modulators, leading to higher signal-to-noise ratios. Their experimental results demonstrate that the F-qubit protocol can achieve high secret-key rates, with a calculated sifted key rate of 1.28 bits per photon in a noisy channel, and show that the phase error rate remains manageable even under adverse conditions. Furthermore, the F-qubit basis is overcomplete, containing more states than the standard BB84 protocol, which provides a more robust framework for error detection and characterization in high-dimensional systems. The study concludes that this qubit-like state approach significantly simplifies the preparation and detection stages of HD-QKD without sacrificing the inherent benefits of high-dimensional encoding, such as increased information capacity and higher tolerance to channel noise. By demonstrating a practical and efficient alternative to MUBs, the paper provides a feasible pathway for scaling quantum communication networks using various degrees of freedom, including time-bins and OAM, which are essential for future global-scale quantum secure communications and the development of a quantum internet. This work highlights how tailored state preparation can overcome traditional hardware limitations, offering a versatile tool for enhancing the performance of quantum cryptographic systems in real-world, noisy environments.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/research/fourier-qubits/featured_4D_HD_Pubs_crop.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting atmospheric turbulence for secure quantum communications in free space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/turbulence-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/turbulence-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Atmospheric turbulence represents the primary obstacle to the implementation of large-scale free-space quantum communication networks because environmental aberrations distort the optical information carriers and limit the ability to establish secure links between distant parties. In this research paper, the authors introduce a recurrent neural network called TAROQQO specifically designed to forecast turbulence strength within an optical channel to identify the optimal timing for secure communication. The study is grounded in a robust dataset of weather and turbulence parameters collected over a nine-month period across a 5.4-kilometer intra-city free-space link in Ottawa, Canada. Unlike previous empirical models or neural networks that were limited by seasonal data or fixed-time predictions, TAROQQO offers a flexible computational toolbox capable of outputting predictions up to twelve hours in advance with a minute-by-minute time resolution. This high resolution is critical for capturing the rapid temporal variations in the refractive index, quantified by the structure parameter, which causes scintillation, beam wandering, and wavefront distortion. To demonstrate the practical implications of these predictions, the researchers performed numerical simulations of a high-dimensional quantum key distribution protocol using the BB84 framework. This protocol utilized spatial modes of light, specifically orbital angular momentum states, which are highly sensitive to atmospheric conditions. By analyzing the performance of these states across different turbulence regimes, the authors were able to infer a specific turbulence threshold under which a real-world experiment can be conducted successfully. The simulation results showed how aberrations induce crosstalk and reduce power transmission, but by using TAROQQO to predict the channel&amp;rsquo;s behavior, researchers can make informed decisions about when to initiate a key exchange. This predictive capability optimizes the use of experimental resources and reduces costs by avoiding periods of unfavorable atmospheric conditions. The study highlights that the network&amp;rsquo;s training on real night-time and multi-season data allows it to generalize effectively across varying environmental states. Furthermore, the researchers suggest that while the primary focus is on quantum key distribution, the TAROQQO framework is broadly applicable to any free-space optical experiment involving structured light or satellite-to-ground communication. The paper concludes that integrating recurrent neural networks into the management of quantum networks is a vital step toward reliable ground-to-ground and ground-to-satellite configurations. By providing a method to validate the turbulent channel in advance, the authors have created a tool that ensures secure communication links are only established when the atmospheric conditions permit high-fidelity transmission. This research ultimately bridges the gap between theoretical quantum communication and the practical challenges of deploying such technologies in unpredictable urban environments, offering a path forward for more resilient and efficient quantum networking infrastructure. Through the combination of longitudinal environmental sensing and advanced machine learning, the work provides a comprehensive strategy for overcoming the stochastic nature of the atmosphere in the pursuit of secure global communication.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/research/turbulence-prediction/featured_taroqqo.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast adaptive optics for high-dimensional quantum communications in turbulent channels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/fast-ao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>lukasscarfe@gmail.com (Lukas Scarfe)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/fast-ao/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we showed that the use of a fast adaptive optics system in a high-dimensional quantum key distribution setup allows for secure communications even in the presence of significant noise .</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:1313/research/fast-ao/featured.png" />
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
